[opening theme song playing]
BLUE BOX
EPISODE 14
WHAT'S THE CONNECTION?
[coach] Our second game is tomorrow.
We will be facing
last year's champion, Minatozaki.
Frankly, this is going to be
a tough one for us.
But they're not unbeatable.
Keep your heads in the game, everyone.
[all] Yes, sir!
[indistinct chatter]
[pleasant music playing]
- [Kikuchi] Nagisa, Chinatsu.
- [both] Huh?
I'm counting on you tomorrow.
Our first win was thanks to the points
that you both put on the board.
But those only happened
'cause of assists from the other players!
Okay, then this time,
score without an assist.
[grunts]
So nonchalant and yet so savage.
[Nagisa sighs]
By the way, did you hear the rumor?
It sounds like Yoshitani and Koike
are going to retire after nationals.
What?
They gotta focus on entrance exams.
That's why we need to do well,
so they can keep playing
as long as possible.
I haven't confirmed it all
with the two of them myself yet,
- I heard it arou--
- [rustling]
Huh?
[Nagisa] Roly-poly Natsu?
FYI!
I haven't seen this
since our last game of junior high.
CHINATSU CURLS UP UNDER PRESSURE!
Hello in there.
You don't have to bear this
all on your own, you know.
I can't help it.
[Nagisa sighs] It's 'cause
she keeps her feelings inside.
I mean, she finally made it to nationals,
but it meant not living with her family.
And she may be a second-year,
but she's a promising scorer,
so she must be feeling
the pressure more than anyone.
[mellow music playing]
Nagisa.
Basketball is fun, right?
Well, duh.
Yeah... duh.
[Chinatsu] Up until nationals,
I had doubts
lurking in every corner of my mind.
But then we played the first game,
and won,
and I had such an adrenaline rush.
Totally.
But that was only possible
because of all the time
we spent practicing.
Yoshitani passed me the ball,
Koike set a screen,
and I was able to get a clear shot.
Then when I missed, you got the rebound.
And at that moment, I thought...
I wanna keep playing ball like this
for forever.
[Nagisa] You're asking for the impossible.
Now then,
up with you, young lady!
You could have let me
lie down a little longer.
You can't play ball
if you're not standing up!
Look at your bracelet,
you're gonna make it cry!
[exclaims softly]
[inaudible]
[Chinatsu] It'll be fine.
I'll have my act together tomorrow.
[Nagisa] If you don't, we're in trouble.
[boy] Taiki, the court's all yours!
Okay!
In the end,
Hyodo took home the championship, huh?
At least, Haryu lost his game
to the champion.
No! Don't let him
overhear you saying that.
- [whimpers]
- Huh?
So now, girls' basketball's
the only team with a chance.
Was their game at 4:00?
What's the latest with Hina?
How's she doing?
Now that you mention it,
I haven't heard back from her.
I did send her a text
before the competition.
[Coach Yuasa] All right, everybody.
The gym is scheduled for repairs today.
So make sure that all of you
are out of here by four o'clock.
[all] Yes, sir.
[Taiki] I'm not
forgetting anything, right?
[gasps softly]
I wonder what Chinatsu's doing.
Maybe she's warming up.
[yells]
That's not a good sign!
I've got until 4:00.
I have to score at least once!
[grunts]
Huh?
It doesn't matter
what kind of "bad sign" I'm seeing.
Chinatsu will make her shots.
After all, she's been practicing non-stop
every single day.
She's a year older than me,
does things at her own speed,
and has a weird sense of personal space.
It can be hard to tell
what she's thinking,
but not when she's embracing
her childlike side.
She's sensitive and considerate,
almost to a fault,
hates losing more than anything.
And when she's playing basketball,
she looks so cool.
That's the Chinatsu who I...
I... like.
[yells]
[breathing heavily]
What the hell am I doing?
Am I mumbling out the first draft
of my confession?
I don't wanna hear myself
being all serious like that!
Especially out in public!
[screams]
And I still can't get myself
to say any of this to her face!
[groans]
Oh, man, this bums me out
on so many levels.
[Hina] What's with all the commotion?
[grunts]
Hina!
Hi!
The gymnasium is closed off
for the rest of the day.
Obviously.
I only came because they told me
to report my results
from nationals to the principal.
[Taiki] Our school is really uptight
about that kinda thing, huh?
So anyway, how'd you do?
- Taiki!
- [grunts softly]
Buy me taiyaki.
Taiyaki?
[announcer on PA]
The game between Minatozaki Academy
and Eimei Private High School
will now begin.
[blows whistle]
[players] Let's play a good game!
- [giggles]
- I was confused
when you wanted taiyaki in the summer,
but I totally get it now.
Red bean paste and soft-serve ice cream
are a match made in heaven!
Nationals are over now,
so I get a cheat day!
[exclaims]
I can feel the sugar in my veins!
Ah!
[Taiki] She isn't telling me
how she placed.
Maybe she didn't do as well as she wanted.
If she'd done well,
she would've told me first thing.
Maybe this is her stress-eating.
- By the way, I got third.
- Huh?
Third place?
I hadn't told you yet, so...
I figured I should tell you how I did.
[Taiki] She's just gonna
drop it on me like that?
But getting third place is amazing!
That's third in Japan, right?
Do I look like someone
who'd be happy about this?
My mistake.
[Hina] I placed higher than last time,
and I can recognize
that my performance has gotten better.
But next time around, I'll place higher.
I just think it's admirable
that you're not letting the win
go to your head.
But as an outsider, third place
is a huge accomplishment already,
so let me do this for real...
Congrats, Hina!
[Hina] Hm.
Thanks.
[grunts softly]
[Taiki] Why is she making that face at me?
[chuckles] Let's go eat
at that park over there!
Wait for me!
Right now,
they're probably in the third quarter.
MINATOZAKI - EIMEI
That was so good!
Thanks again, Taiki!
You're welcome.
[Hina gasps]
The swings are open! [giggles]
[laughing]
[Taiki] I'm glad she's having a good time.
[exclaims]
Quit it!
Hm?
Uh... What for?
- I almost saw your underwear.
- What?!
I have shorts under my skirt!
That isn't really the point, Hina!
'Cause you're a girl!
You gotta be careful about this stuff!
Well, that's new.
You treating me like a girl.
I treat you like a girl.
You are one.
Are you checking the time?
Uh, no, I wasn't...
[gasps]
Could it be that Chinatsu's game is today?
Huh?
Mm. Yeah, it is.
[all cheering]
[Taiki] They must be
in the fourth quarter by now.
They're, apparently,
playing last year's champions.
I've heard this game
is a big one for Eimei.
Yup. Yup.
[grunts softly]
Having said that,
it's not as if I can do anything.
[sighs] Okay.
So let's compete in a shoe-toss!
What's the connection?
Since Chinatsu's competing right now,
you should be competing too.
That's the connection.
Don't look at my undies, okay?
Of course I won't.
If you lose,
you have to tell me something
that you haven't told anyone.
What?
Wait, we're betting on this game?
[Hina] And I already know
about training camp
during the first year of junior high.
[Taiki] Don't bring that up!
Okay, you go first.
[Taiki] It's good she's having fun, but...
I don't know... There's something different
about Hina today.
[hopeful music playing]
[Chinatsu grunts]
Some serious air.
What an amateur!
The whole point is to try
to get it to go far, not high.
[chuckles] Are you an expert or something?
[all cheering]
EIMEI
MINATOZAKI
'Kay!
My turn now!
[Chinatsu panting]
Natsu!
You don't have to go easy on me.
[Nagisa] Let's go!
[Hina] I've got this!
[music stops]
- [buzzer sounds]
- [ball thudding]
[all cheering]
[Hina] I've never told anyone this, but...
I like you.
- [buzzer sounds]
- [all cheering]
[laughing]
[panting]
[whimpers]
[sobbing]
[Chinatsu] It didn't come true.
My wish didn't come true.
I like you, Taiki.
Um... uh...
In, like, a...
romantic way?
A romantic way.
[laughs]
As your best friend,
I caught you unawares, huh?
I mean, honestly,
I, for one, was surprised by this, too.
I was like, "Really? Taiki?"
You know?
So in your face! Surprise!
[gasps softly]
- [sizzles]
- What is that look?
It's just out of nowhere.
I don't know what to think,
I'm pretty caught off-guard.
And this is the first time someone's
confessed their feelings to me.
I'm just blushing over here.
It's just completely out of left field.
[chuckles softly]
Look, I know that you have
feelings for Chinatsu.
So I don't need an answer right away.
It's just... I didn't think
anything would change unless I told you.
So stop looking at me as your best friend.
From now on,
see me as a girl who likes you.
[Taiki gasps]
[Hina] Well, that's that,
so I'm heading home!
[Taiki] Huh?
You can buy me a parfait
if I place first next year!
[Taiki] Uh, Hina!
[happy piano music playing]
- [vending machine clanging]
- [coin jingling]
[beeps]
[clattering]
[groans]
Having someone confess to me
has my heart pounding.
Hina likes me...
Were there signs that I missed?
And how long has she liked me?
Did she already have feelings for me
when we went to the fireworks festival?
[gasps] Say that again!
[groans]
When I think that she already...
liked me at that point,
[sighs] it feels like
a sucker punch to the chest.
Knowing what I know now,
I've been kind of a jerk, huh?
And maybe then too?
That's what...
[Hina grunts hesitatingly]
that's what makes you great.
[Taiki] Hina's great.
As a friend, an athlete, and a person.
She's easy to talk to, earnest,
and someone I can respect.
And that describes the person who...
[groans]
INOMATA
- Don't do that where people can see you.
- And what is it you think I'm doing?
- Strength training?
- That's not what I'm doing.
I'm back!
[Taiki] I don't want my mom to see me
while I'm agonizing over romantic stuff.
Oh, I got a text, by the way.
From Chinatsu.
They lost their game.
[sad piano music playing]
[Taiki gasps softly]
[gasps softly]
When she gets back,
tell her we know she gave it her all.
[Taiki] Yeah.
CHINATSU
[Taiki] What's going on?
I haven't done anything wrong,
so why do I feel so guilty?
I don't even know how I'm supposed to act...
the next time I see her.
[Taiki] What a relief.
Gymnastics has the day off today.
If I ran into Hina right now,
I don't think I could look her in the eye.
I just need a little time to...
[gasps softly]
[sighs]
[Hina] Here we go!
[groans]
Hey! What are you looking at?
You're standing at the entrance,
there's nowhere else to look!
Plus, you don't have practice today.
Well, I didn't come here for practice.
[exhales]
You could have
just announced yourself, you know.
It's not that easy!
Uh-huh. And why's that?
It's, because, you know...
[Hina] Ah, yes.
You sit on that, Taiki.
Every time you see me from now on,
your heart should skip a beat.
It's not gonna skip a beat.
Even if it doesn't,
that's fine, as long as it reminds you...
that I have a crush on you.
[Taiki gasps]
Your heart skipped a beat just now.
No, it did not!
Excellent.
Seems like my confession
was pretty effective.
[Taiki] What? Don't say that out loud!
[closing theme song playing]